// An Array To store quiz question and answer //
// Question from Science //
var quiz = [
         	{question: "Who is Known as the father of taxonomy ?",
         	answer1: "Carlous von Linnaeus",
         	answer2: "Carlous Von",
         	answer3: "Von Linnaeus",
         	answer4: "Robert Hook",
         	ans: 1},

         	{question: "Classification of organisms was first done in the year.",
         	answer1: "1950",
         	answer2: "1760",
         	answer3: "1750",
         	answer4: "1850",
         	ans: 3},

         	{question: "The second name of species is also called ",
         	answer1: "Generic Name",
         	answer2: "Phylum",
         	answer3: "Genus",
         	answer4: "Epithet",
         	ans: 4},

         	{question: "The first Letter of the genus should be ",
         	answer1: "Small",
         	answer2: "Capital",
         	answer3: "Number",
         	answer4: "Vowels",
         	ans: 2},

         	{question: "What is the Scientific name of Potato ?",
         	answer1: "<u>Solanum</u> <u>tuberosum</u>",
         	answer2: "Solanum tuberosum",
         	answer3: "<u>Solanum</u> <u>Tuberosum</u>",
         	answer4: "solanum tuberosum",
         	ans: 1},

         	{question: "Who proposed five kingdom system ?",
         	answer1: "Robert Hook",
         	answer2: "Robert H. Whittaker",
         	answer3: "Carlous Von Lannaeous",
         	answer4: "H. Whittaker",
         	ans: 2},

         	{question: "Which of them below belongs to Monera Kingdom",
         	answer1: "Mushroom",
         	answer2: "Amoeba",
         	answer3: "Paramecium",
         	answer4: "Cynobacteria",
         	ans: 4},

         	{question: "Which type of bacteria is found on extreme environment",
         	answer1: "Archaebacteria",
         	answer2: "Eubacteria",
         	answer3: "Cynobacteria",
         	answer4: "Bacteria are not found on extreme environment.",
         	ans: 1},

         	{question: "Which is the Locomotory organs of amoeba ?",
         	answer1: "Pseudopodia",
         	answer2: "Cilia",
         	answer3: "amoeboleg",
         	answer4: "Flagella",
         	ans: 1},

           	{question: "Fungi Store their in the form of ...",
         	answer1: "Stomatch",
         	answer2: "yest",
         	answer3: "Glycogen",
         	answer4: "Chitin",
         	ans: 3},

         	{question: "The combination of algae and fungi is called ...",
         	answer1: "Yeast",
         	answer2: "Mucur",
         	answer3: "Mushroom",
         	answer4: "Lichen",
         	ans: 4},

         	{question: "Fungi that absorbs nutrition from other is called ...",
         	answer1: "Saprophytic Fungi",
         	answer2: "Parasitic Fungi",
         	answer3: "Symbiotic Fungi",
         	answer4: "Chlorofillus fugi",
         	ans: 2},

         	{question: "The Underground thallus part of the mushroom is called ...",
         	answer1: "Mycelium",
         	answer2: "Stipe",
         	answer3: "Pileus",
         	answer4: "Trama",
         	ans: 1},

         	{question: "Which is the inner fleshy portion of mushroom's basidiocarp ?",
         	answer1: "Gills",
         	answer2: "Hymenium",
         	answer3: "Trama",
         	answer4: "Pileus",
         	ans: 3},

         	{question: "The fingers like projection of basidium is called ...",
         	answer1: "Sterigmata",
         	answer2: "Basidium",
         	answer3: "Mycelium",
         	answer4: "Gills",
         	ans: 1},

         	{question: "Which is the reproductive part of the mushroom ?",
         	answer1: "Umbrella",
         	answer2: "Stipe",
         	answer3: "ring",
         	answer4: "Fruiting Body",
         	ans: 4},

         	{question: "There are ... types of strained in spores.",
         	answer1: "Thirteen",
         	answer2: "Three",
         	answer3: "Two",
         	answer4: "Fourteen",
         	ans: 3},

         	{question: "Which is the most common cultivated mushrrom in nepal ?",
         	answer1: "Pleurotus Ostreatus and Agaricus bisporus",
         	answer2: "Amnita Bisporus",
         	answer3: "Amanita phalloides and omphalotus illudens",
         	answer4: "All of the above",
         	ans: 1},

         	{question: "Yellow slime in the pileus means ... Mushroom",
         	answer1: "Tasty ",
         	answer2: "Good For Health",
         	answer3: "Poisonous",
         	answer4: "Nothing",
         	ans: 3},

         	{question: "Which is the Edible Mushroom",
         	answer1: "Amanita phalloides",
         	answer2: "Amanita species the destroying angles",
         	answer3: "Omphalotus illudens",
         	answer4: "Caesar's Mushroom",
         	ans: 4},

         	{question: "What is the formula to calculate speed ?",
         	answer1: "Time/distance",
         	answer2: "Distance Travelled/ Time Taken",
         	answer3: "Velocity/ Time",
         	answer4: "Time/ Displacement",
         	ans: 2},

         	{question: "What is the value of Acceleration due to gravity on earth ?",
         	answer1: "8.9 m/s<sup>2</sup>",
         	answer2: "10 m/s<sup>2</sup>",
         	answer3: "9.8 m/s <sup>2</sup>",
         	answer4: "20 m/s <sup>2</sup>",
         	ans: 3},

         	{question: "In Which axis does time is written in displacement-time graph ?",
         	answer1: "Y Axis",
         	answer2: "Z Axis",
         	answer3: "W Axis",
         	answer4: "X Axis",
         	ans: 4},

         	{question: "Inertia of an object is directly proportional to its ...",
         	answer1: "Force",
         	answer2: "Velocity",
         	answer3: "Mass",
         	answer4: "Time",
         	ans: 3},

         	{question: "The external force which produces a chnage in length, volume, and shape of body is called ...",
         	answer1: "Restoring Force",
         	answer2: "Deforming Force",
         	answer3: "Centrifugal Force",
         	answer4: "Centripetal Force",
         	ans: 2},

         	{question: "What is the SI Unit of Charge ?",
         	answer1: "Newton",
         	answer2: "Current",
         	answer3: "Voltage",
         	answer4: "Columb",
         	ans: 4},

         	{question: "What is the SI Unit of Resistance ?",
         	answer1: "Columb",
         	answer2: "Ohm",
         	answer3: "Farad",
         	answer4: "Ampere",
         	ans: 2},

         	{question: "In which circuit current's is divided ?",
         	answer1: "Short Circuit",
         	answer2: "Domestic Circuit",
         	answer3: "Parallel Circuit",
         	answer4: "Series Circuit",
         	ans: 3},

         	{question: "",
         	answer1: "",
         	answer2: "",
         	answer3: "",
         	answer4: ""}
         	];
         	

// Declaring variable//
var questionarea = document.getElementById("question");
var a = document.getElementById("answer1");
var b = document.getElementById("answer2");
var c = document.getElementById("answer3");
var d = document.getElementById("answer4");
var timearea = document.getElementById("time");
var scorearea = document.getElementById("score");
var livesarea = document.getElementById("lives");
var score = 0;// Initial Score //
var initiallives = 3// Initial lives//
var quiztime = 5;// Time interval of quiz contest//
var lives = initiallives;
var time = quiztime;
var questionlist = 0;
var wronganswer = 0;
var upcommingin = 1500;// (In milli second) This variables shows for how long the next question will come after click the button//

// A function to load question //
function loadquestion(){	
	questionarea.innerHTML = quiz[questionlist].question;
	a.innerHTML = quiz[questionlist].answer1;
	b.innerHTML = quiz[questionlist].answer2;
	c.innerHTML = quiz[questionlist].answer3;
	d.innerHTML = quiz[questionlist].answer4;
	questionlist++;
	livesarea.innerHTML = "Lives : "+lives;
	scorearea.innerHTML = "Score : "+score;
	timearea.innerHTML =  questionlist + " out of " + (quiz.length-1);
	if(questionlist==quiz.length){
	gameover();
}
}



// A function to disabled answer button click //
function disable(){
	a.style.pointerEvents = "none";
	b.style.pointerEvents = "none";
	c.style.pointerEvents = "none";
	d.style.pointerEvents = "none";
}
// A function to enabled answer button click //
function enable(){
	a.style.pointerEvents = "";
	b.style.pointerEvents = "";
	c.style.pointerEvents = "";
	d.style.pointerEvents = "";
	loadquestion();
}



// Checking Which button is clicked by the user using function parameter //
function answer1(inp){
	disable();
	setTimeout(enable,upcommingin);
	checkanswer(inp);
}
function answer2(inp){
	disable();
	setTimeout(enable,upcommingin);
	checkanswer(inp);
}
function answer3(inp){
	disable();
	setTimeout(enable,upcommingin);
	checkanswer(inp);
}
function answer4(inp){
	disable();
	setTimeout(enable,upcommingin);
	checkanswer(inp);
}





// A checkanswer() function to check answer is correct or not with question database //
function checkanswer(answer){
	var correctans = quiz[questionlist-1].ans;
	if(answer==correctans){
		correct(answer,correctans);
		score++;
		scorearea.innerHTML = "Score : "+score;
		// playing Correct_answer.mp3 if answer is correct //
		var audio = new Audio();
		audio.src = "correct_answer.mp3";
		audio.play();
	}else if(answer!=correctans){
		// playin wrong_answer.mp3 if answer is not correct //
		var wrongaudio = new Audio();
		wrongaudio.src = "wrong_answer.mp3";
		wrongaudio.play();
		wronganswer++;
		// nested if else to check lives //
		if(lives>1){
		lives--;
		livesarea.innerText = "Lives : "+lives;
		}else{
			gameover();
		};

		wrong(answer,correctans);
	};
}


//This function will execute when user's input is wrong //
	function wrong(wrong,correctans){
		var answer = wrong;
		if(answer==1){
			a.style.backgroundColor = "red";
			setTimeout(()=>{a.style.backgroundColor = "white"},upcommingin);
		}else if(answer==2){
			b.style.backgroundColor = "red";
			setTimeout(()=>{b.style.backgroundColor = "white"},upcommingin);
		}else if(answer==3){
			c.style.backgroundColor = "red";
			setTimeout(()=>{c.style.backgroundColor = "white"},upcommingin);
		}else if(answer==4){
			d.style.backgroundColor = "red";
			setTimeout(()=>{d.style.backgroundColor = "white"},upcommingin);
		};

		if(correctans==1){
			a.style.backgroundColor = "green";
			setTimeout(()=>{a.style.backgroundColor = "white"},upcommingin);
		}else if(correctans==2){
			b.style.backgroundColor = "green";
			setTimeout(()=>{b.style.backgroundColor = "white"},upcommingin);
		}else if(correctans==3){
			c.style.backgroundColor = "green";
			setTimeout(()=>{c.style.backgroundColor = "white"},upcommingin);
		}else if(correctans==4){
			d.style.backgroundColor = "green";
			setTimeout(()=>{d.style.backgroundColor = "white"},upcommingin);
		};	
	}


// This function will Execute when user's input is correct //
	function correct(correct,cor){
		var answer = correct;
		var correctans = cor;
		// Changing background color according to input//
		if(answer==1||quiz[questionlist-1].ans==1){
			a.style.backgroundColor = "green";
			setTimeout(()=>{a.style.backgroundColor = "white"},upcommingin);
		}else if(answer==2||quiz[questionlist-1].ans==2){
			b.style.backgroundColor = "green";
			setTimeout(()=>{b.style.backgroundColor = "white"},upcommingin);
		}else if(answer==3||quiz[questionlist-1].ans==3){
			c.style.backgroundColor = "green";
			setTimeout(()=>{c.style.backgroundColor = "white"},upcommingin);
		}else if(answer==4||quiz[questionlist-1].ans==4){
			d.style.backgroundColor = "green";
			setTimeout(()=>{d.style.backgroundColor = "white"},upcommingin);
		};
	}


// A function for game over //
function gameover(){
	var overelement = document.getElementById("game-over");
	var finalscore = document.getElementById("final-score");
	var correct = document.getElementById("correct");
	var wrong = document.getElementById("wrong");
	var totalqn = document.getElementById("totalquestion");
	let len = quiz.length - 1
	wrong.innerHTML = "Wrong : "+wronganswer;
	correct.innerHTML = "Correct : "+score;
	finalscore.innerHTML = "Score : "+score;
	totalqn.innerHTML = "Total Q.N : "+len;
	if(overelement.classList=="invisible"){
	overelement.classList.remove("invisible");
	overelement.classList.add("visible");
	}else{
		overelement.classList.remove("visible");
		overelement.classList.add("invisible");
	};
}